<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lochana Perera</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lochana Perera</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle&#39;s Nicomachean Ethics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/nicomachean-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/nicomachean-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aristotles-nicomachean-ethics-or-how-to-not-be-a-jerk&#34;&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Nicomachean Ethics, Or: How to Not Be a Jerk&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-note&#34;&gt;Programming Note&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this expecting tips on tax-efficient charitable giving strategies, I have bad news. Nicomachean Ethics is not about the tax code. It&amp;rsquo;s about how to live a good life, which, depending on your perspective, might be either more or less complicated than the tax code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-basic-trade&#34;&gt;The Basic Trade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Look, here&amp;rsquo;s the fundamental problem Aristotle was trying to solve. Everyone wants to be happy, right? But nobody can agree on what happiness &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;. Some people think happiness is money. These people work at investment banks.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Other people think happiness is pleasure. These people also work at investment banks, but in different departments. Still others think happiness is honor, which, I mean, good luck with that in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy in America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/democracy-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/democracy-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;democracy-in-america-is-weird&#34;&gt;Democracy in America Is Weird&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So there was this French guy, Alexis de Tocqueville, who showed up in America in 1831, supposedly to look at prisons but really to figure out what the deal was with democracy. And look, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking: &amp;ldquo;Why do I care what some 19th-century French aristocrat thought about America?&amp;rdquo; But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing — the guy basically invented political science Twitter 200 years early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hobbes&#39;s Leviathan, or How to Not Murder Each Other Over Politics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/leviathan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/leviathan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-context-or-why-everyone-was-so-upset&#34;&gt;The Context, or Why Everyone Was So Upset&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s 1651 and Thomas Hobbes has just watched England tear itself apart for like a decade.The English Civil War (1642-1651)&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/event/English-Civil-Wars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was basically what happens when you take the question &amp;ldquo;who should be in charge?&amp;rdquo; and answer it with &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s find out with swords.&amp;rdquo; King Charles I thought God wanted him to run everything. Parliament thought, no, actually, we should have a say. The Puritans thought everyone else was doing Christianity wrong. The Catholics were nervous. The Scots were involved somehow. It was a mess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machiavelli&#39;s Other Book Is About Republics Actually</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/discourses-on-livy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/discourses-on-livy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;    src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/exp/images/mach.webp&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;&#34;&#xA;    &#xA;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-context-thing&#34;&gt;The Context Thing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s a fun story about Niccolò Machiavelli. Everyone knows him as the &amp;ldquo;ends justify the means&amp;rdquo; guy who wrote &lt;em&gt;The Prince&lt;/em&gt;, that cynical handbook about how to be a ruthless dictator. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Machiavelli actually preferred republics! I know! The guy whose name literally became an adjective for scheming political manipulation spent most of his intellectual energy writing a massive love letter to republican government. It&amp;rsquo;s like finding out that Gordon Gekko&amp;rsquo;s favorite book was actually about credit unions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/kitchensink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/kitchensink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post demonstrates all the awesome Markdown features supported by this Hugo site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-and-links&#34;&gt;Text and Links&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This paragraph contains &lt;strong&gt;bold text&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;italic text&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;del&gt;strikethrough text&lt;/del&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;inline code&lt;/code&gt;. You can also include &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/my-first-post/&#34;&gt;internal links&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com&#34;&gt;external links to Google&lt;/a&gt;, which get a special icon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;blockquote&#34;&gt;Blockquote&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be, or not to be, that is the question: Whether &amp;rsquo;tis nobler in the mind to suffer the slings and arrows of outrageous fortune, Or to take arms against a sea of troubles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ovid&#39;s Metamorphoses, or: How to Get Exiled for Writing Fanfiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/metamorphasis-ovid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/metamorphasis-ovid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Look, so around 8 CE, Publius Ovidius Naso—Ovid to his friends, probably &amp;ldquo;that guy who won&amp;rsquo;t shut up about Zeus turning into animals&amp;rdquo; to everyone else—finished writing what is essentially the world&amp;rsquo;s most ambitious mythological cinematic universe. The &lt;em&gt;Metamorphoses&lt;/em&gt; is 15 books of people turning into things, gods behaving badly, and what happens when you give shapeshifting powers to entities with impulse control problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;    src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/exp/images/ovid.webp&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;&#34;&#xA;    &#xA;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-context-is-everything&#34;&gt;The Context Is Everything&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing about writing in Augustan Rome: Augustus Caesar had just spent decades transforming Rome from &amp;ldquo;republic that&amp;rsquo;s definitely still a republic, why do you ask?&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;empire but we don&amp;rsquo;t say the E-word out loud.&amp;rdquo; The whole Roman project at this point was about transformation—transforming chaos into order, transforming a mess of civil wars into the Pax Romana, transforming Augustus from &amp;ldquo;guy who proscribed his enemies&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;Father of the Fatherland.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/exp/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is some content to show off the styling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-is-a-subheading-h2&#34;&gt;This is a Subheading (H2)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a paragraph of text. It can contain &lt;strong&gt;bold text&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;italic text&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;inline code&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are a wealthy nation, the political economist tells the poor&#xA;man, and our superfluous wealth must find employment somehow&#xA;or other. Hench the crush of high-stepping horses, the crowd of&#xA;three-hundred-guinea barouches; the flutter of costly garments rustling&#xA;in the summer air, the glitter and splendour which pervades every&#xA;object, until it seems almost as if the superfluous gold were melted&#xA;into the atmosphere, and all the female population were so many Miss&#xA;Kilmanseggs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
